(571) 523-3345 McLean, Virginia ytyeung@gwu.edu

Yat To Yeung, Bosco

Ouantitative Social Scientist/ PhD Candidate

Website: ytyeung.com linkedin.com/in/yeung317

Dedicated and experienced researcher in Asian American identity politics and regulatory politics in Greater China. Keen to leverage quantitative and survey research skills in real-life settings and provide evidence-based solutions to drive positive change.

SKILLS

Tools and Languages

R, Stata, SQL, ŁTFX, Tableau, Qualtrics, Python

Quantitative Research
Communication

Causal Inference, Machine Learning, Surveys and Experiments (A/B Test), Data Visualization

English, Cantonese, Mandarin

WORKING EXPERIENCE

PHD CANDIDATE

AUG 2019 — Present

George Washington University

Washington, DC

- Developed an original survey experiment of 1000 respondents to examine the effectiveness of electoral strategies in campaigns.
- Performed qualitative content analysis of 6000+ public consultation documents in mainland China, Hong Kong, and Taiwan to examine differences in approaches to civic engagement and regulation.
- Created an original field experiment and analyzed large survey data with 10000+ respondents to study government responsiveness.
- Collaborated with 10+ researchers across multiple disciplines on projects that examines Chinese government responsiveness and online hate and anti-vaxx communities in the US.
- Lectured undergraduate students in R tutorial sections and mentored 20+ undergraduate students on semester-long R project.

DATA ANALYTICS INTERN

JUN 2022 — AUG 2022

Hanover Research

Arlington, Virginia

- Performed data cleaning and created linear and logistic regression models to analyze individual- and group-level factors that influence students' academic outcomes and graduate rates.
- Reviewed formatting and data accuracy in key client deliverables, such as Tableau dashboards and reports.
- Worked with Research Associates and Content Analysts to collect information for use in reports and determine the scope of work for clients.

JUNIOR RESEARCHER JUN 2018 — AUG 2018

European Institute for Asian Studies

Brussels, Belgium

- Utilized existing data set to co-author a quantitative report on Taiwanese foreign investment in the European Union, commissioned by the Taiwanese Representative Office in Belgium and the EU to promote Taiwan-EU trade.
- Provided operational support to event organization (workshops and briefing seminars).
- · Participated in conferences and seminars organized by think tanks (Bruegel), the European Parliament, and embassies.

ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICER (INTERN)

JUN 2017 — AUG 2017

Home Affairs Department of Hona Kona SAR Government

Hona Kona SAR

- Conducted a qualitative comparative study on homeless policy in Canada, Denmark, Hong Kong, Singapore, U.K., and U.S.
- Refined the Facebook page of the Sham Shui Po Youth Corps by providing recommendations to the District Officer.
- Participated in the District Council meetings and the public administration of the HKSAR.

SUMMER INTERN

JUN 2016 — AUG 2016

The European Chamber of Commerce in Hong Kong

Hong Kong SAR

- Conducted research on financial technology policies and automotive industry, particularly in Hong Kong and the European Union, for the Business Councils' position papers
- Assembled a report on electric vehicles in Hong Kong for the bilateral negotiation between the EU and HK govt (report presented to the Financial Secretary of Hong Kong and led to the reconsideration of EV subsidies).
- Partnered with and interviewed major automotive manufacturers, fintech, and law firms as part of the research.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy in Political Science, George Washington University	May 2024 (expected)
Master of Philosophy in Political Science, George Washington University	2023
Master of Arts in Political Science, George Washington University	2022
Summer Program in Quantitative Methods of Social Research, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor	2021
Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, Politics and Economics, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor	2018

SELECTED PRESENTATIONS

American Political Science Association Annual Meeting	2023 (scheduled)
Frontiers in Empirical Research on East Asia at New York University	2023 (scheduled)
Northeastern Political Science Association Annual Meeting	2021
Midwest Political Science Association Annual Meeting	2021, 2022
Western Political Science Association Annual Meeting	2021